nabp.pharmacy 2019-06-24

# Privacy Policy | National Association of Boards of Pharmacy

## Privacy Policy

 _Last Updated: November 12, 2018_

##### Introduction

The National Association of Boards of Pharmacy® (NABP®) or National Association of Boards of Pharmacy Foundation® (NABPF®) operates one or more websites (Website), such as [www.nabp.pharmacy](http://www.nabp.pharmacy/) or [www.nabp.net](http://www.nabp.net/). NABP and NABPF are collectively referred to as “NABP.” Information about you may be collected through the Website. NABP may operate one or more software applications (App) that may collect information about you. The Website and App are collectively referred to as “Site.”

Information privacy and security are important to NABP, and NABP respects the personal information that you, as a user of the Site or NABP services, may share with us from time to time. This Privacy Policy (Policy) applies to user-identified information (Personal Information) that NABP may collect through the Site, affiliates, or products or services offered by NABP. NABP may amend this Policy at any time and at its sole discretion. NABP will post the amended Policy on the Site and will include the “Last Updated” date to reflect the effective date of the latest amendments. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of an amended Policy signifies your acceptance of the terms of the Policy as amended.

Please review the Policy and the [Terms of Use](https://nabp.pharmacy/policies/terms-of-use/), which apply to your use of the Site.

##### INFORMATION COLLECTED

NABP offers many services (Services), including educational, informational, examination, accreditation, licensure, registration, promotional, and subscription Services. NABP may ask you to provide Personal Information to complete a transaction or may use Personal Information to deliver Services. For example, if you request to register for an examination or meeting, or if you request a subscription related continuing pharmacy education, NABP may collect Personal Information such as your name, email address, or payment information to complete the registration or subscription that you requested.

The types of Personal Information that may be collected include:

  * First and last name;
  * Address;
  * Email address;
  * Telephone number;
  * Social security number;
  * Government-issued identification card number;
  * Payment-related information such as a credit or debit card number;
  * Educational data, such as the school or college of pharmacy from which you graduated, graduation date, internship hours, or continuing pharmacy education;
  * Professional information, such as your license or registration, certification information, or licensure or registration history;
  * Employment-related data;
  * Information such as your date of birth, login credential, or password;
  * Law enforcement-related information such as licensure or registration discipline, or sanction, exclusion, or criminal data;
  * Internet Protocol (IP) address;
  * Data related to your use of the Site, including click stream behavior (ie, the Site webpages that you view, the links that you click, and other actions that you take in connection with the Site), incident reports such as software crash reports;
  * Publicly available data;
  * Information requested by a licensing agency;
  * Data or information that may be particular to NABP Services; or
  * Information that you may authorize NABP to collect.

NABP may collect non-Personal Information during your visit to the Site. This information includes, but is not limited to, certain standard data that your browser sends to the Site such as your browser type and version, device type, language, access times, and the IP address of the website from which you arrived at the Site.

NABP may engage third-party service providers to support, provide, or administer Services, including the Site. These service providers may collect Personal Information on behalf of NABP or receive Personal Information from NABP. For example, NABP engages a third-party service provider that collects email addresses from individuals who subscribe to _NABP e-News_.

NABP might store some information on your computer hard drive in the form of a “cookie” to assist you with purchasing Services from NABP, to speed the log-in process, or to store information, such as personal preferences. Additionally, NABP’s third-party service providers may use information obtained through “cookies” for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Site, compiling reports on Site activity and Internet usage. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. Please note, that if you refuse the use of cookies you may not be able to use the full functionality or Services of the Site.

When you pay for Services, credit card information may be collected by NABP through its Site, or you may be securely transferred from the Site to an NABP third-party service provider, which may collect your credit card information or other Personal Information for the purpose of processing your payment on behalf of NABP. Credit card information which is obtained by NABP through its Site is handled securely, in accordance with applicable laws and regulations, as well as payment card industry standards for such information.

##### USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

NABP uses Personal Information to deliver the Services you have requested, as you may permit from time to time, to contact you on behalf of boards of pharmacy, to contact you about your e-Profile, NABP account, or use of the Site, or for Association operations, including quality assurance purposes, to deliver to you information about NABP, or promotional activities.

Personal demographic and profile data may be used to tailor your experience at the Site, for example, to show you content you might be interested in.

NABP may use publicly available Personal Information about you for any purpose permitted under applicable law.

NABP may share your Personal Information with licensing agencies including, but not limited to, boards of pharmacy or pharmacy technician certification organizations if you are a certified pharmacy technician. For example, NABP may make your continuing pharmacy education data available to a board of pharmacy or pharmacy technician certification organization.

NABP may share your Personal Information with regulatory or law enforcement agencies as permitted or required by law.

NABP may disclose your Personal Information if required under the law or to comply with legal process, to protect or defend NABP rights, property, staff, or members, or the rights, property, or safety of others.

NABP may provide third-party service providers with your Personal Information for purposes of delivering the NABP Services you request, for third-party services that you may request, or to support, provide, or administer Services, including the Site. For example, NABP may provide your name, address, and phone number to our testing vendor if you request examination Services through the Site. NABP may provide your name and email address to a marketing organization to provide you with information about NABP Services.  Such third parties are required to protect your Personal Information in conformance with applicable state and federal laws. The privacy policy of such providers may apply to their use of your information. The provider’s policy may differ from this Policy, and you may wish to review the provider’s privacy policy or contact the provider directly for more information.

In the course of conducting Association business, NABP staff may access Personal Information for the purposes stated in this Policy. Staff are required to maintain the confidentiality of non-public Personal Information and are prohibited from unlawfully disclosing such information.

NABP may use or share de-identified data about users of the Site or Services for one or more purposes described in the Policy.

NABP does not sell Personal Information to third parties.

When your Personal Information is no longer needed, NABP disposes of it using methods to protect the security and confidentiality of the Information data, such as shredding, erasing, or rendering the Information to be unreadable.

#####  **DO NOT TRACK DISCLOSURES**

NABP does not respond to users’ web browsers that communicate a “do not track” signal to the Site. The use of tracking technologies by third-party service providers on the Site is not covered by the Policy. These providers may use cookies or other methods to support their tracking technologies; however, NABP does not control these tracking technologies.

##### CORRECTING/UPDATING INFORMATION

You may request changes to Personal Information previously provided to NABP, or notify NABP of the preferred method by which NABP contacts you, by contacting NABP Customer Service via:

  * Email: [help@nabp.pharmacy](mailto:help@nabp.pharmacy)
  * Phone: 1-847/391-4406
  * Fax: 1-847/375-1114
  * Postal mail: 1600 Feehanville Dr, Mount Prospect, IL 60056

When notifying NABP of a change in sensitive Personal Information (such as social security number or credit card information), NABP requests that you call or send a facsimile (fax) communication to NABP Customer Service.

##### OPT-OUT

If you prefer that NABP not contact you with information about NABP or promotional materials, you may opt-out by contacting NABP Customer Service via:

  * Email: [help@nabp.pharmacy](mailto:help@nabp.pharmacy)
  * Phone: 1-847/391-4406
  * Fax: 1-847/375-1114
  * Postal mail: 1600 Feehanville Dr, Mount Prospect, IL 60056

##### THIRD-PARTY LINKS

The Site may contain links to third-party websites that are not controlled by NABP. These third-party links are made available to you as a convenience and you agree to use these links at your own risk. Please be aware that NABP is not responsible for the content or operations of third-party websites linked to NABP, nor is NABP responsible for the privacy policies or practices of third-party websites linked to the Site or NABP.

##### SECURITY

NABP utilizes industry-standard measures to protect Personal Information under our control from misuse or unauthorized access. For example, NABP uses encryption technology to protect Personal Information that it collects through the Site; however, NABP cannot guarantee that these measures will fully protect the Personal Information. NABP will take all reasonable steps to protect the safety of your Personal Information.

##### OPERATIONS

Our Site and the servers that make the Site available world-wide are located in the United States. The laws of the US govern all matters relating to and all transactions involving the Site. Any information you provide in registering or purchasing goods or Services from NABP will be transferred to the US. By visiting the Site and providing information to NABP through your use of the Site, you authorize this transfer, processing, and use of information.

##### AGREEMENT WITH PRIVACY POLICY

By using Services or logging onto or using the Site, you signify your agreement to the terms of the Policy and any modifications thereof and that you release and hold harmless NABP, its members, directors, officers, employees, contractors, and affiliates from any and all claims arising from information that you provide or transmit to NABP or the Site in an unsecured manner.

Your use of the Site is governed by the Policy and the [Terms of Use](https://nabp.pharmacy/policies/terms-of-use/).

If you have any questions about the Policy, the practices of the Site, NABP Services, or your interactions with the Site, you can contact NABP via email at [help@nabp.pharmacy](mailto:help@nabp.pharmacy) or via phone at 1-847/391-4406.

  * Policies
